♪Looking in the mirror,
my temples have turned white♪
♪Taking off the hairpins and makeup,
shedding the disguise♪
♪A cold face♪
♪With two lines of tears♪
♪If an actor could gain pity♪
♪The audience offers sincere words♪
♪Perhaps the story could be changed♪
♪The storyteller says♪
♪This mortal world is full of turmoil♪
♪Within sight but beyond reach♪
♪Yet I still don't want to give up♪
♪Don't let the memory be hollowed out♪
♪Don't make me ridiculous♪
♪Some vows turn into smoke
and fade away♪
♪Even the leaves know when autumn comes,
but you don't even know me♪
♪Imprisoned in plight,
yet still full of passion♪
♪I mock this absurd and entangled love♪
♪How can I bear to let go♪
=Whispers of Southern Song=
=Episode 6=
You're awake?
Where are you going?
I...
Are you okay?
Are you going to see Rong Xiaonan?
Mr. Rong learned too much today.
He was agitated.
I...
I need to comfort him.
I took a bullet for you,
so how would you comfort me?
You got hurt saving me, Young Marshal.
I will remember this kindness
and repay it.
How will you repay me?
Judging by your condition,
Young Marshal, you're fine anyway.
Don't move.
Young Marshal!
It better be important.
The Governor wants to see you.
(Loyalty)
This character "loyalty"
seems to be missing a dot.
Without that dot,
it's no longer the character "loyalty".
(Loyalty)
You only taught me how
to hold a gun, not how to hold a pen.
You botched the Buddha Head case
and killed Xiaosheng Society's envoy.
Now you've killed Adjutant Zhao as well.
You! You're out of control!
Today, I'll teach you
how to write this character "loyalty".
Do you want a loyal fool
who's useless, or a gun that works?
Only I can help you
retrieve the Jade Buddha Head.
(Need him to find Buddha Head and trade
for Phoenix Crown. Can't kill him yet.)
You're quite like me.
How is it?
Having your life in someone else's hands
isn't pleasant, right?
So, do you want
to sit in the Governor's seat?
Yes!
Good!
I'll give you one last chance.
Find the Buddha Head
for me within five days,
and I'll give you the Governor's seat.
You get along well with Jiang Chun'er.
Your wedding is in five days.
If you find the Buddha Head for me,
she will be your wife.
But if you fail,
she can still be my wife.
Young Marshal, are you okay?
Go count our men.
Whether for power or for our lives,
we need to have a backup plan.
Yes.
Mr. Rong.
Rong...
Miss Jiang.
Mr. Rong.
I saw you were sleeping deeply,
so I didn't wake you.
Are you okay?
Miss Jiang, don't worry.
I was just overly worried.
Thank you.
Before, I only saw you
as just another face in the audience.
These days, I've finally understood.
There is no one else in this world
who treats me as well as you do.
In the future,
if you ever need anything,
even if I have to walk through fire
and tread on blades, I'll get it done.
Mr. Rong, you're too polite.
I really don't want anything in return.
Young Marshal, what is this?
I was injured for Miss Jiang.
Miss Jiang ought to repay me
by taking care of me.
Since you also want to take care of
Mr. Rong, why don't I stay with him,
so you won't be stretched too thin?
I can also keep Mr. Rong company.
If you want to stay here, I'll let you.
Let me?
In this Governor Mansion,
do I need your permission to stay here?
If I hadn't helped you escape,
I'm afraid you'd still be rotting
in that dungeon, Young Marshal.
Don't you see it?
You walk free in Governor Mansion now.
And who do you have to thank?
Enough!
I see you both are fine.
Take care of yourselves.
So, what brings you here?
I just came to remind you, Mr. Rong,
don't forget the Jade Buddha Head.
Young Marshal, you said before,
that if you help me find who killed
my master, you'll get the revenge.
The murderer is Xu Fan.
Once you keep your word
and take his life,
I will naturally help you
retrieve the Jade Buddha Head.
What evidence do you have?
I can see the blood debts
soaked into things.
That day, I touched the fake one,
and saw the saber go into Master's chest.
But I still couldn't see
the murderer's face.
Until yesterday, when I touched
Adjutant Zhao's sidearm,
I finally confirmed
the murderer is Xu Fan.
Just based on
your superstitious nonsense,
you want me to raise my sword
against the man who raised me?
I don't need you to believe me.
If you break your word, you won't
find the Jade Buddha Head through me.
And I will kill Xu Fan
with my own hands.
You want to assassinate
the Governor in his mansion?
Don't you see
what your situation is right now?
Even if you fight like a trapped beast,
you should weigh your own strength.
Mr. Rong.
Miss Jiang.
What's wrong?
After Adjutant Zhao captured Yue Niang,
the child was killed.
Mr. Rong.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Miss Jiang, please rest assured.
This "Tale of Vindication" hasn't
reached the dragon-slaying yet.
(Governor Mansion)
Stop!
This way!
- Yes.
Young Marshal.
Someone attempted to assassinate
the Governor.
We are ordered to search.
You actually dared to make a move?
In this situation,
should I call you brave or stupid?
Young Marshal.
Are you okay? Young Marshal.
Mr. Rong, are you willing
to cooperate with me now?
- We're coming in!
- One more chance.
Are you okay, Young Marshal?
Do you want to live or die?
- You think I'll still trust you?
- Young Marshal.
Then go die, Mr. Rong.
Are you okay, Young Marshal?
Governor.
Break it open!
Foster Father.
What brings you here personally?
Someone tried
to assassinate me just now.
I wounded him and he fled.
Did you notice anything unusual?
No.
Search.
Search thoroughly.
Check over there.
Open that one.
Check carefully.
Even search the bathtub.
Insolent!
Xu You'an, negligent in duty
and in violation of military code,
shall receive fifty lashes
as a warning to all.
♪If an actor could gain pity♪
♪The audience offers sincere words♪
♪Perhaps the story could be changed♪
♪The storyteller says♪
♪This mortal world is full of turmoil♪
♪Within sight but beyond reach♪
♪Yet I still don't want to give up♪
♪Don't let the memory be hollowed out♪
Take care, Foster Father.
♪I mock this absurd and entangled love♪
♪How can I bear to let go♪
♪As if it were fate♪
♪Deliberately playing tricks♪
♪We miss each other♪
♪Creating a turbulent drama♪
♪And a bizarre♪
♪Anonymous legend♪
♪The plot twists and turns♪
♪Play out over and over again♪
♪Waiting to be discarded♪
♪And you are like a moth to the flame♪
♪Refuse to submit♪
♪I can't bear to blame you♪
♪There are always too many♪
♪Helpless situations♪
♪Overwhelmed by time♪
♪Even if I have questions♪
♪I harbor desires♪
♪Nowhere to find answers♪
♪People come and go♪
♪I'm still all alone♪
♪Wandering around♪
♪Fortunate to have you with me♪
♪Go through the entanglement♪
♪If longing♪
♪Turns into dust and smoke♪
♪How can I be at ease♪
♪Having walked through prosperous times♪
♪And travelled around the world♪
♪Scars all over me♪
♪If longing never fades♪
♪Burns still hot♪
♪Let it turn into dust and smoke♪
♪After half a lifetime of loneliness♪
♪In the next life♪
♪Entangle with you again♪